Bowers, Mollie H. Grievance and Mediation Documents 5942
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Mollie H. Bowers Grievance and Mediation Documents
1950-1986
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Bowers, Mollie H.
5942
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Records (documents).
5736595
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 03, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 18, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5456: Mollie H. Bowers Collection of Arbitration and Fact Finding Decisions Regarding Police and Fire Fighters 5568: Mollie H. Bowers Police and Firefighter Arbitration
Grievance arbitration; Mediation and conciliation, Industrial; Bowers, Mollie
5736595
- Correspondence, 1977-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bowers, et al. A Data Based Inquiry Into State Mediator Perceptions of Grievance Mediation, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Mollie H. Bowers, Lawson Savery, and Lamont E. Stallworth. August, 1981
- Bowers, et al. An Empirical Inquiry Into State Mediator Perceptions of Grievance Mediation, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Mollie H. Bowers, Lawson Savery, and Lamont E. Stallworth. May, 1981.
- Bowers, et al. Grievance Mediation: A Route to Resolution for the Cost Conscious 1980's, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Mollie H. Bowers, Ronald L. Seeber, Lamont E. Stallworth. Draft of a paper presented at the 35th Annual Spring Meeting of the Industrial Relations Research Association, April 28-30, 1982.
- Bowers. Grievance Mediation: Settle Now, Don't Pay Later, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  March and October, 1979
- Bowers. A Proposal for Providing a Grievance Mediation Service for the Federal Sector, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  September, 1981
- Bowers. The Role of Mediation In Grievance Resolution, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  February, 1977
- Bowers. The Use of Mediation to Resolve Grievances, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  April, 1980
- Contract Administration Book Correspondence, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Research Materials: Articles and Book Chapters, 1950-1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Research Materials: Articles and Book Chapters, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Research Materials: Articles and Book Chapters, 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Mediation Questionnaires (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous Notes (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Mostly handwritten
- Anderson. The Impact of Public Sector Bargaining, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Address by Arvid Anderson, Chairman, Office of Collective Bargaining, to the Great Lakes Assembly, march 30, 1973
- George Buckingham (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Research proposal and research objectives
- Brett and Goldberg. An Experiment in the Mediation of Grievances, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Jeanne M. Brett and Stephan B. Goldberg. January, 1982
- Gregory and Rooney. Grievance Mediation: A Trend in the Cost Conscious Eighties (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Gordon A. Gregory and Robert E. Rooney
- Hoffman. Mediation Against Unfair Dismissal Grievances: The British Example, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Eileen Barkas Hoffman. Draft of paper presented to the Industrial Relations Research Association, December 28, 1979
- Kassalow. Public Employee Bargaining in Europe: What Lessons for the United States, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Everett M. Kassalow. Paper presented at the Industrial Relations Research Association, December 19, 1968.
- Kochan. A Framework for the Study of the Effectiveness of Mediation, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Thomas Kochan. Draft of a Working and Discussion Paper, October 4, 1974.
- Kochan. Further Discussion of the Mediation Research, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Thomas Kochan. Working Paper, April 7, 1975.
- Kolb. Roles Mediators Play: Comparisons and Contrasts in State and Federal Mediation Practice, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Deborah M. Kolb. March, 1980
- McGrady. Conciliation, mediation and voluntary arbitration are the marks of industrial civilization (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Edward F. McGrady
- Piore. Unions and Politics, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Michael J. Piore. Paper prepared for the Conference on the Future of Unionism in Manufacturing in the 1980's, June 21-23, 1978
- Prihar. Contract Administration: Roles and Functions (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Michael Prihar
- Savery and Stallworth. Codebook for Grievance Mediation Study, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  Lawson Savery and Lamont E. Stallworth. December 11, 1980
- Weiss. Expedited Arbitration, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  Barry N. Weiss. Paper for Dr. Bowers' class, BMGT 763, April 4, 1977.
- Grievance Mediation: A New Alternative in Grievance Resolution (Box 1, Folder 29)
- A Grievance Mediation Service for the Federal and Public Sectors, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  August, 1983
- Mediation of Grievances: A Summary Description of an Experimental Plan (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Mediation Procedures and Techniques (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Mediation Research and Education Project (Box 1, Folder 33)
  Two papers: Some Questions and Answers and Presentation Outline.
- A Multivariate Analysis of Advocate and Mediator Attitudes Towards Grievance Mediation (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Neutrality Clauses (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1977-1986 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Reports, 1978-1982 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- United Steelworkers Grievance Agreements, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Abstracts and Outlines (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Bibliographies (Box 1, Folder 40)
  Separated from the papers they belong to.
- Pages from unknown papers (Box 1, Folder 41)
  Three sets. One begins with page 3; one begins with page 17; and one begins with page 31.